Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Donald B. Armstrong Papers, 1966-1973 RL.11136
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Donald B. Armstrong papers
1966-1973
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.11136
0.4 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Donald Armstrong was an advertising executive with J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), Young & Rubicam, and McCann-Erickson/Interpublic agencies.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Harvard class of 1937; Lehn & Fink 1937-1939; Young & Rubicam 1937-1945; McCann-Erickson (Interpublic)1946-1963; joined JWT 1963; Co-Director of JWT Review Board 1966; Executive Vice President, JWT 1971; retired 1977. Died 1990.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Donald B. Armstrong papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a [gift/purchase/transfer] in [year].
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following J. Walter Thompson Company Archives collections held in the Hartman Center:
Account Files; Detroit Office. Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports; International Offices; New Business Records; New York Office Records; Wallace Elton Papers.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1966-1972 and includes correspondence, research reports and other printed matter. Companies represented include Ford and Congoleum. Report topics include Puerto Rico, South Africa and the JWT Chicago Office. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
J. Walter Thompson Company; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States; J. Walter Thompson Company
- Detroit Office--1972 Review of JWT-Ford Division Advertising Research (Box 1)
- Detroit Office--A Proposal for a More Effective Marriage of Marketing Research to Marketing Planning, 1972 (Box 1)
- Detroit Office--Research from Yankelovich re Ford Torino and Pinto consumer information, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Detroit Office--The Role of Market Communications in Selling Automobiles, 1971 (Box 1)
- New Business--Puerto Rico, 1969 (Box 1)
- New York Office--Draft of an open letter to David Ogilvy, 1972 (Box 1)
- New York Office--Executive Dining Room, 1972 (Box 1)
- New York Office--Media Department, 1972 (Box 1)
- New York Office--Review of Print Advertising Campaigns of Congoleum-Nairn and Key Competitors, 1966 (Box 1)
- South Africa Office--Circle newsletter and organizational chart, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Southern California Gas Company/Southern Counties Gas Company, 1967 (Box 1)
- Target Group Index (AMRB), 1972 (Box 1)
- Testing Advertising (Draft), 1971 (Box 1)
- The Anatomy of a Commercial, 1969 (Box 1)
- Use of Television for Corporate Advertisers (draft), 1972 (Box 1)
- Women and Consumer Initiatives, 1972 (Box 1)